Guide to the George B. Ehlhardt Collection on Robert Frost, 1916-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
George B. Ehlhardt Collection on Robert Frost 1916-1980
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ehlhardt, George B., collector.
0.8 linear feet Extent: 42 Items
Reverend George Brinkmann Ehlhardt received his theological degree from Duke Divinity School in 1945. Reverend Ehlhardt was librarian of the Duke Divinity School Library from 1942 to 1950 and was later appointed president of Brevard College. This collection, collected mostly by George Ehlhardt, Duke Divinity School Librarian, includes ephemera and periodicals containing material by or about the American poet Robert Frost.
RL.00422
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George B. Ehlhardt collection on Robert Frost were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Biographical Note
Reverend George Brinkmann Ehlhardt received his theological degree from Duke Divinity School in 1945. Reverend Ehlhardt was librarian of the Duke Divinity School Library from 1942 to 1950 and was later appointed president of Brevard College.
Collection Overview
This collection, collected mostly by George Ehlhardt, Duke Divinity School Librarian, includes ephemera and periodicals containing material by or about the American poet Robert Frost. It is arranged in the order of the originally assigned Frost collection number found on the envelopes.
Subject Headings
Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Poets, American; Ehlhardt, George Brinkmann
Contents of Collection
- Ephemera and periodicals, 1916-1980, (2 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
  Contains ephemera and periodicals including material about/by Frost that were mostly collected by George Ehlhardt.
  - House of books, ltd. Firm, Booksellers, New York, 4 leaves clipped from the March, 1951 catalog of books for sale, Frost items for sale as listed. (Box 1)
  - Parke Bernet Balleries Inc. Bernheimer auction of Frost material (Box 1)
  - The month at Goodspeed's. 1943 January (Box 1)
  - Amherst graduates' quarterly. 1936 August and 1948 August (Box 1)
  - Amherst graduates' quarterly. 1924 August and 1929 August (Box 1)
  - Amherst graduates' quarterly. 1935 November and 1936 May (Box 1)
  - Amherst. 1978 Winter (Box 1)
  - The old farmer's almanac, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The seven arts. 1916 November (Box 1)
  - American prefaces. 1939 April (Box 1)
  - Biblia. 1938 February (Box 1)
  - Atlantic. 1951 June (Box 1)
  - Atlantic monthly. 1947 April (Box 1)
  - Atlantic monthly. 1947 November (Box 1)
  - The archive. 1943 February (Box 1)
  - Saturday Review. 1959 March 21, 1962 March 24, and 1963 February 23 (Box 2)
  - Touchstone. 1939 February (Box 2)
  - Scopus. 1963 June (Box 2)
  - Cleland, James J. A love that wanted re-renewing. 1968 June 2 (Box 2)
  - Library notes. 1945 April (Box 2)
  - New masses. 1945 July 31 (Box 2)
  - Time. 1950 October 9 (Box 2)
  - Athens College bulletin. 1961 November (Box 2)
  - Boston arts festival program. 1954 June (Box 2)
  - Lankes, J J. Three wood engravings (Box 2)
  - The New Hampshire troubadour. 1946 November. Two letters from Thorsten V. Kalijarvi to Rev Ehlhardt (Box 2)
  - Robert Frost his poems, portraits and printers 1913-1963 a comprehensive exhibit (Box 2)
  - Robert Frost at Agnes Scott College (Box 2)
  - George Ehlhardt's speech on the evening of 1947 Feb 27 on his presentation of his Frost collection to Duke (Box 2)
  - Amherst alumni news. 1963 Fall (Box 2)
  - The hampshire bookship 1916-1936 twentieth anniversary week (Box 2)
  - An Evening's Frost' program of this theatre presentation by University of Dubuque. 1967 April 6 (Box 2)
  - Program of Frost 75th birthday exhibition Friends of Duke Library. 1950 March 26 (Box 2)
  - Calendar of Duke University. 1943 January 24-30 (Box 2)
  - The Choate alumni bulletin. 1962 Summer (Box 2)
  - Program of a Frost reading by Friends of the Duke Library. 1945 March 14 (Box 2)
  - Program of a Frost reading by Friends of the Duke Library. 1947 February 27 (Box 2)
  - Amherst. 1980 Summer (Box 2)
  - Durham news clippings (Box 2)
  - Mark Twain quarterly. 1940 Spring (Box 2)
  - New York Times Book Review. 1949 May 29 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Portrait of Robert Frost (Opaperfolder 1)